Downloaded @ subs4free.club
[MUSIC]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Be gentle, Hannah.
[MUSIC]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Invoke you by your
great names to come to our aid.
Defeat the Romans, destroy their
ships, their engines of war, and their soldiers.
We will prevail.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[MUSIC]
I know.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
You did not make an offering today.
I prefer to sacrifice a Roman.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[MUSIC]
[BLANK_AUDIO] Where you are, I am too.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[MUSIC]
[BLANK_AUDIO] And where you
are, I am too, forever, my wife.
[MUSIC]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The wind is too strong.
Furl sail and strike water.
Furl sail, strike water.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Strike water.
[MUSIC]
They have no lands
but the ones they've stolen.
Wherever they go, they
leave destruction and call it peace.
[BLANK_AUDIO] This is the
last free city in Africa, Nova.
Today, we go into battle.
Pray that your God is with
you, if he is not, he is no God.
[LAUGHTER]
We've nothing to
fear, but death is, we are not.
But we are.
Death is not.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Stay together and listen for my command.
Rise up and you're head out.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[MUSIC] [BLANK_AUDIO]
[INAUDIBLE]
Release.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[BLANK_AUDIO] [BLANK_AUDIO]
Raise the tower.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Back to stone.
Drop, drop range.
The drop range is stuck.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[BLANK_AUDIO] [BLANK_AUDIO]
I'll wait for you.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
What damage have they done you?
Lift up.
Easy, easy.
Hold that.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Alley shots.
I am sorry my son.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Hmm.
I have not long.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
This galley is sailing
us to something I cannot endure.
I am ready to be taken to another place.
Stay here a while longer.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I remember well when
you first were brought to us.
A lonely boy from the
desert, guileless, afraid.
You embraced everything we taught you.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
You found that he shut love.
Your soul was replenished.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
When I die, my ancestors
will meet me in the next world.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Who will meet you?
I know.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I am done.
Do not let them change what you are.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[LAUGHTER]
[ Dolores screaming] [ LalOLLE screaming]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[ALARM beeps]
[MUSIC THReads Do Bit]
[Me to the dont power] (thunder rumbling)
You seen this boy?
(dramatic music)
Imo, Imo!
You must go alone now, Hano.
Never let them find you.
Go, go.
(dramatic music)
(singing in foreign language)
(crowd chanting)
In Brigata.
Emperor Caracol.
General Acasis.
I have taken Numidia in your names,
but your dominion may
eclipse that of every emperor
that came before you.
Crown him with laurels, brother.
(crowd cheering)
In honor of your conquest,
there will be games in the Colosseum.
I require no games in my honor.
Serving the Senate and the people of Rome
is honor enough for me.
You are too modest, Acasis.
Does not suit a general
as accomplished as yourself.
Your glory is yours, not mine.
I only ask for some respite from war
to spend time with my wife.
Your wife, yes.
Remember the
privileges we have granted her?
Where is she now to
ignore such an occasion?
There are victories yet still to come.
Persia.
India.
Both must be conquered.
Rome has so many subjects.
She must feed them.
They can eat war.
(horn blaring)
Your triumphs will be celebrated
as a tribute to the
greatness of the Roman people.
(crowd cheering)
(intense music)
Macrinus of
Fisters, master of gladiators.
(crowd cheering)
(intense music)
No mistake votes.
(crowd cheering)
You go out of the town councilors.
Distinguished guests.
You gotta write a
pack, citizens of Antia.
Behold the fate of
the conquered enemies of Rome.
The barbarian, you
idiots, and their chief,
their new god, Lord.
(intense music)
(crowd cheering)
(screaming)
(intense music)
[screaming]
Which one is interesting?
[screaming] [screaming]
I'll fire.
[screaming]
Hold.
Here goes there.
General.
[music playing]
My lady.
I thank the gods that
brought you back home safe.
Thank the army they protected me.
Let me feed you.
[screaming]
Go.
To the wall.
The arena is a sacred temple.
For the bravest of you, the
road to glory runs through the arena.
The arena turns slaves into
gladiators and gladiators into free men.
You have worms.
I know this one.
He eats monkeys.
[thunder]
Go. Sit. Eat.
[whimpering]
[screaming]
You.
I know. Get up.
What is your native
language? I speak them all.
You don't answer because
you can't or because you won't.
All right.
Violence is the universal language.
Vigo, put him through his paces.
He can fight an ape.
Let's see if he can fight a man.
[sighing]
[laughing]
[grunting]
The arena!
Very good.
Close him down.
Bring him to me.
Ah!
Strong jaw.
Good arms.
Better smell.
Ah, you would do well.
It is an art.
Choosing gladiators.
Some choose entertainers.
Some choose brute force.
I choose rage.
Crowd loves blood and they love
those who love blood as much as they do.
And you, my friend, rage,
pours out of you like...
like milk.
From a horse tit.
You will be quite the fighter.
Not for you.
You're right. You do not fight for me.
I put you in the ring. You
fight or you die. The choice is yours.
But whose head could I give
you that would satisfy this fury?
The entire Roman armies.
[laughing]
Too much.
The general will do.
General?
General Acacis?
Use your rage in my service, then
you will have his head ready for your sword.
Serve me and host serve you. Deny me.
And you will die.
At times I will wish you the best.
You should abandon me
rather than fight their wars.
I've made my choice.
I can live with it.
But my patience
with those two is at an end.
Letter.
You may go to your quarters now.
We need nothing more.
To hear wives and mothers
mourning their dead on that beach at Numidia.
Silla.
No more.
I will not waste another
generation of young men for their vanity.
If I fight another
campaign, it must be to depose them.
When will your troops arrive?
We landed Austrian ten days.
How many of them
will be loyal to you alone?
All of them.
The empress do not
have the support of the people.
The people are weary of
the madness, of the tyranny.
What is the dream of Rome?
That people are not free.
Enjoy yourselves, everyone.
To excess.
Thank you.
Wow.
Please.
Drink.
Ah!
Excuse me.
I knew the
provinces were not enough for you.
I'm just here for the games.
Ah, well.
You won't be disappointed.
Rome has all the games
that men like you like to play.
Men like me, Thrax, men like us.
I know nothing happens in
Rome unless you've tasted it first.
[crowd cheering]
How's my purpose here?
We'll find out. It's only now.
What's this we hear
about you being interested
in standing for
election to the Senate, Macalus?
Me? No. No, I'm not.
I don't even know how to use an abacus.
But I do understand that it's
customary for your guests to make wages.
How large a sum did you have in mind?
A thousand gold denarii?
Two.
Two?
Denarii.
Mmm.
Stand back!
My emperors, lords,
ladies and gentlemen, and senators,
for your
entertainment, the art of combat.
May I present the barbarian
versus from my own stable, the mighty Vitek!
[crowd cheering]
This is your radiator.
It is.
Three rounds, hand to hand. Swords!
We want swords to fight to the death.
No quarter to be
offered or given. Fight now.
Brother, I am the king of the gods.
Let's not kill each
other for their amusement.
[crowd cheering]
[yelling]
[crash]
[crowd cheering]
[crowd cheering] [crash]
[CRASHING]
[GUNSHOT]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Remarkable!
Drex, you looked expensive for her.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Remarkable.
From where do you hail?
Speak.
I said speak.
He is from the colonies.
Your Majesty, his native
tongue is all he understands.
The gates of hell are open night and day.
Smooth is the descent and easiest away.
But to come back from hell
and view the cheerful skies in this,
the task and mighty labor lies.
[PANTING]
Virgil, your Majesty.
Poetry!
[LAUGHTER]
Very clever, my goodness.
Thank you.
I've grown so
bored, but you surprised me.
To amuse you is my only wish.
We are amused. We are amused.
We are amused.
And we all look forward to
seeing your poet perform in the arena.
As do I, your Majesties.
Thank you.
Vigo, come with me.
[PANTING]
You fought well
today, but you were lucky too.
The lines you recited.
You didn't learn
that in Africa. I know that.
A good verse travels far.
Who taught you poetry?
A captioned Roman officer.
I was posted guard over him, and
he used to tell us tales to pass the time.
And what became of this prison?
How we ate him.
As barbarians do.
And where were you born?
Why does my past matter if it is
my future to die for you in the arena?
Tell me what you survive for Roman money.
A gladiator can buy his own freedom.
His liberty.
The Roman dream.
The slave dreams not of
freedom, but of a slave to call his own.
Cicero.
Is that what you
were raised on, Maccrelas?
What did you have to do for Roman money?
You promised me a head.
Earn your keep and
you can have anyone's head.
Father, protect us and guide us.
Senators.
My lady.
I wish we were meeting in better times.
Better times will come.
And why are we here?
To take back the city.
And restore Rome to where she should be.
An exciting venture.
When? On the final day of the games.
When? On the final day of the games. When?
On the final day of the games.
My army waits for my command at Ostia.
Five thousand soldiers loyal to me.
We'll enter Rome and then the
Colosseum where they will arrest the emperors for
their crimes against
the Senate and their people.
This plan is ambitious and risky.
Rome will be yours
to administer and to...
Marcus Aurelius talked of
restoring power to the Senate.
But that was a
generation ago. Much has changed.
The people have not seen hope.
For many years.
But with time.
And guidance.
Lucilla, you are the
daughter of Marcus Aurelius.
He had my loyalty.
And so do you.
Senator Thraxx.
Politics follows power, my lady.
Take back what is rightfully yours.
And the Senate will support you.
Thank you.
When I was told of this
place, you never mentioned the stink.
That would be Hanos.
Well, you'll have
to put up with me as I am.
And what's that up there? A wolf?
The twins there, they were outcasts.
Left in the hills to die.
That wolf found them.
She suckled them on her milk.
Raised by an
animal that's in their blood.
How do you know this place?
I know the chaos they brought.
This city infects everything it touches.
I never dreamt it would be so big.
Don't fall for it. This city is diseased.
The No way!
Ah!
Stare speakers and happy honeyfuckers.
Ah, the barbarian.
I haven't forgotten.
I always repay my debts.
I was merely going to suggest
that perhaps your luck might change,
shall we say double of things.
(laughing)
(dramatic music)
(yelling)
Light up, light up.
(dramatic music)
Lay, lay.
(horn blaring)
(cheering)
Emperor Katicala,
Emperor Gator,
citizens of Rome.
These sacred games are
held to honor the victory of Rome
over the barbarians of Numidia.
(yelling)
And honor Rome's legionary commander,
General Eustace Acacius.
(cheering)
And with him, Lucilla,
the daughter of Emperor Marcus Aurelius.
(cheering)
Acacius.
General.
(cheering)
Speak to them.
I am not an orator or a politician.
I am a soldier.
I've seen bravery in
men and women during war,
and even once in this arena.
So if you ask anything of the gods,
ask for that same bravery.
(dramatic music)
Because Rome needs it now.
(cheering)
From the South Gate,
bakers from the
stable of Matronos of Vistrus.
(cheering)
From the stables of
Emperors Calicalla and Gator themselves,
the undefeated
champion, Glissero the Destroyer.
(explosions)
(dramatic music)
Oh!
(cheering)
(explosions)
(cheering) (explosions)
Oh!
Help, Jesus!
(explosions)
(cheering)
Hold together and when
the charges break for the wall.
Why should I?
(explosions) Hold, hold!
Cows!
(explosions)
(cheering)
(yelling)
(explosions)
(groaning)
(yelling)
(explosions)
(laughing)
(growling)
(cheering)
(explosion)
(growling)
(explosions)
(yelling)
(yelling) (yelling)
(explosions)
(yelling)
Brother, is that poet, is it not?
I can't remember.
That night was a blur.
The gates of hell are open night and day.
Smooth as I forget.
Smooth as the scent.
Easy as the way.
Kill!
(explosions)
(yelling)
Brother.
You sit.
Shall we show mercy?
Mercy.
(yelling)
(explosion)
No mercy!
Your life has been spared by the gods.
I will sooner face your blade
than accept Roman mercy.
(yelling)
(explosion) (yelling)
Kill!
(yelling)
(explosion)
The road to freedom
doesn't run through the arena.
Leads to this.
Go to yourself.
(yelling)
(panting)
Now let's go.
Gates of hell are open night and day.
Smooth as the descent.
Easiest away.
Dad, Dad.
And I bought you an
maximus, the single road.
(somber music)
It's got to end our gentle.
(explosion)
(somber music)
Lucius is safe.
Lucius.
(somber music)
(screaming)
Lucius.
You're the sole heir to the throne now.
There are men who want to
kill you so they can take power.
I promise I'll bring
you back as soon as I'm safe.
Mother, why can't you come with me?
I have to stay here for your sake.
I'm here for the sake of room.
Remember who you are and that I love you.
I love you.
Come.
Give me your leg.
Go, go.
(screaming)
So.
(somber music)
What's your name?
I'm Ravi.
I'm Doctor.
Because more men die of infected wounds
than out there in the arena.
This needs to be
cleaned, needs to be stitched,
and it is going to hurt.
This is devil's breath and opium.
It's for the pain you should breathe in.
I've been here so long now.
They don't even notice anymore.
I've done more
amputations than I can count.
Where do you learn your trade?
Why do you ask?
You've got a heavy hand.
I used to be a gladiator myself.
Yeah.
What would you have
bested me in your prime course?
In your current
state, I could best you now.
Luckily for you, I have put down my sword
so now I spend my days saving lives
instead of taking them.
Why such a change so late in life?
What we do in life echoes in eternity.
I feel like I know those words.
I can't take credit.
It's written on one of the tombs.
With the bones of a gladiator.
My champion, I smell devil's breath.
My.
Champion, did you hear that crowd?
Did you hear that crowd?
You have something.
I knew it from the start.
Did you now?
Yes, the Greeks
call it thymos, smoke, rage.
That rage is your gift.
Like the great Achilles, never let it go.
It will carry you
to greatness, my champion.
(fire crackling)
(screaming)
(growling)
Thank you for inviting me.
This is truly an honor.
(water splashing)
I hear you are the talk of the court.
Yes.
We met before.
Have we?
Long ago.
Where?
I was in the
service of your father's army
on this African campaign.
You served with my father.
(groaning)
Hmm.
I had the privilege
of reading his meditations.
Hmm.
The best revenge is to be unlike him
who performed the injury.
I hear you've been
arming half the legions
in the entire
empire, and here, now, in Rome,
you're gaining
influence by sponsoring gladiators.
I do it for the love of the sport.
And where did you find these gladiators?
They're usually
prisoners of war or vagrants.
Why do you ask?
A man can choose to fight and stay alive.
It's the same in life as
it is in the arena, is it not?
Who is this?
That is my father as a youth.
She had a child.
Hmm.
It's common
knowledge when comatose was killed,
the boy disappeared.
Hmm.
Well, he would care.
Silla would care.
More wine!
More wine.
He was of the royal bloodline, after all.
And his father?
Ostensibly.
Lucius Verus.
You see, it was an arranged marriage.
She was 14.
Females were not his taste.
Not mine, some days.
Not yours.
(laughing)
No, no, no.
By rumor, you see, she took lovers,
and by rumor, the
real father was comatose.
Brotherly love, you see.
If he died, there has to be remains.
And if he lived,
that would make him about...
Well, let's work it out.
He was about 12 when he died.
Yes.
So that would make him...
(dramatic music)
My lady.
Crackers.
Here's the cold.
Thank you.
(dramatic music)
Gladiator.
Do you know me?
Hmm.
Do you have a family?
A wife?
Arishat?
She was killed
under your husband's commands.
For all drowns in its own blood.
And yet you enjoy the
pleasures of the Colosseum.
There's much you do not understand.
(dramatic music)
Duchess.
I do not know who you think I am.
My name is Hano, and I have no mother
or none that I can remember.
(dramatic music)
I'm so sorry.
If you're somewhere here,
I would tell you not to grieve him,
for he would not be
the boy that you sent away.
That boy is dead.
You may think I have little worth.
You may think I betrayed you.
But I need you to know,
if you will not have your mother's love
and take your father's strength,
you need it.
His name was Maximus Decimus Mervidius.
And I see him in you.
Get out.
My lady, we must go at once.
It's just you were loved.
By myself and by your father.
Your name was on his lips.
Get out!
(dramatic music)
Lucius is alive.
Are you certain?
Yes.
I know my son.
I spoke to him tonight.
He may be lost to me for what I did.
But he lives.
The third day of the games is tomorrow.
Most fighters won't survive.
The cases.
You must help him.
Help him? Yes.
I failed him then.
I know I did.
I cannot fail him now.
The army is in Ostia.
If we wait a few days.
He could be dead by then.
The cases.
I would willingly give my life forever.
Willingly give my life from...
But I will not give my sons.
One!
And two!
And one!
You won't get far like this.
Just him.
You go.
Go.
Let's see how far you can
go on your own without your team.
Ready?
One!
And two!
Diamond, diamond!
Come on, more!
More!
Leave it.
Just vinegar, my friend. Ah.
There will be no more opium for you.
There is plenty of pain
waiting for you in the next life.
Are you a free man, Ravi?
Free.
I am.
I laid down my sword and I
swore never to pick it up again.
And yet you choose this home.
Mm-hmm.
What was your home before?
But I'm Asi.
And why don't you go back?
I wish I could.
Asi.
I met a woman.
It's always a woman. Afterwards.
She's from Lomdinium, Britannia.
So now, our sons, they speak only Latin.
My daughter's eyes,
they are as blue as yours.
We are Romans now.
I grew up hearing
stories at my grandfather's knee.
He used to talk the dream that was Rome.
It was so fragile,
you could only whisper it.
Or it would vanish.
So...
What was this dream?
A Rome where all could live
under fair law and be protected.
A Rome with the Senate.
A Rome with hope.
Your grandfather, he sounds like a...
Like a dangerous man.
The odds are against you.
The odds are always against me.
Don't worry old man.
You should get some rest.
Your men will need
you to lead them to me.
[dramatic music]
It's about survival!
Survive!
In the name of Poseidon, we
celebrate the glory of naval war.
May your marches be
ready to listen for my command.
We are together as cool as one, yes?
Yes!
Today, we relive the Battle of Salamis!
The Trojans versus the Persians!
[crowd cheering]
Pose out!
And pull!
Pull!
Order on!
Order!
[screaming]
Pull!
On time!
Let's die! Ready?
And two more down!
Push in! Push in!
Get down!
[explosions]
Pull!
Don't shoot!
Ready to ram!
And run!
Freeze!
[screaming]
Get him off!
Everybody, be free!
[screaming]
[explosion]
[screaming] [screaming] [explosion]
[screaming]
Just don't react!
Pull, pull.
[screaming]
In the name of the
Emperor, the victor is...
...Hanno!
Forget this!
Who did this?
It was me!
I did it!
[screaming]
Gaeta will want
retribution for all of you.
Did you learn to shoot the
same place you learned to recite poetry?
Be glad it wasn't me or
that arrow would have found you.
Be seated.
I have news for you.
[music playing]
He's here, sir.
Oh, you're here.
Back in the...
...work.
Yes, I'm listening.
You know this is my house now.
Your debt to me is over 10,000 denarii.
You know that.
I have other things. Cattle. Art!
Truth, then.
What do you want?
Truth. That's what I want.
Nothing happens in
Rome without your knowledge.
You have the senator's trust.
You have Lucilla's trust.
More importantly, you have my trust.
You wish my loyalty.
I own your house.
I want your loyalty.
I...
I have heard of a
plot to dethrone the emperors.
Yes.
But the plan has been delayed.
Our gladiator is to be
rescued from the arena tonight.
I know not one.
I know why. I know who.
Pac.
Quickly.
[ROARING]
Open for the emperor's guard.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
My lady.
Come with us.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Thanks to the civic virtue
of men like Thrax and Macronus,
your insurrection has been revealed.
The honor, the dignitas
that Rome has bestowed upon you,
all this you have
forfeited by your treachery.
Please, the embracada, torture
me if you want, but do not lecture me.
Your name will be forgotten!
Lost to history!
You are damned, Jimmy.
You laugh.
You damn me.
I don't care.
Everything is forgotten in
time, empires fall, so do emperors.
Why wait?
I will guard him!
Come, come!
His death must be public.
Public?
Hang his entrails from
the city gates and crucify her!
Crucify her!
Take them away!
Thank you, Macronus.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
In these last days, I have
come to think of you not as a subject,
but as a true friend.
Thank you.
Thank you so much, but as
a friend, I must counsel caution.
Akatas is a hero of Rome,
crucifixion is for thieves, Christians.
He's too common.
He is a traitor. He must die.
I agree.
Let the gods decide
his fate in the Colosseum.
Let the gods decide.
You know, last night I
woke dreaming of the dark river.
This time, the
first time, I was crossing it.
You know where I come from?
Crossing a river, it represents
forgiveness, it represents salvation.
Oh, where I come from,
it means you're already dead.
As I saw it, I was not afraid.
For someone who was
waiting for me on the other side.
Who is this man?
Scratched out? I'm sorry. What the hell? Who is this man? I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Who is this
man? Who is this man? Who is this man? Who is this man? What is he? Who is this man? Scratched out.
Maximus.
I saw him fight once.
He was magnificent.
My time in the arena, it was after
his, but many still talked of him in with Faz.
Spoke of him.
What he did.
I met him once.
He was kind.
He bowed to no one.
Come with me.
When a rebel
gladiator dies, we bury them.
Here.
What we do in life echoes an eternity.
(SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
This is Argento, Mrs. Scato.
There.
And stop.
For his treason against the lives of the
emperors and the Roman
state, General Eustace Acacia,
an enemy of the people.
We are your ancestors!
(CHANTING)
Ray Victus. General.
Get in!
(CHANTING)
From the vanquished city of Numidia,
the victor of two
conquests in the Colosseum...
Go now. Vay Victus.
(CHANTING)
Hello!
Oh, Lord, any honour I
have, I will give it to you.
It's too late.
The Roman traitor or the barbarian hero?
Let the gods decide.
Vay Victus, wait.
Wait! Wait!
(CHANTING)
I am a vessel.
Fill me with vengeance.
Invite with the betrayal.
(CHANTING)
Pick it up!
No, no, no, no!
We love you, Acacia!
What are you waiting for? He was nice!
(CHANTING)
I know who you are.
Lucius Varys Aurelius.
(CHANTING)
Acacia has raised his hand!
He has surrendered!
Let the gods decide!
(CHANTING)
The gods have rented their judgement.
Do what you must.
But on my death you have to know...
I love your mother, Lucilla.
And your father.
(CHANTING)
Maximus...
I would have died for him.
Kill him!
That's it, babe!
(CHANTING)
Kill him!
Don't kill him!
I can't!
No!
Kill him!
Acacia!
(CHANTING)
No!
Acacia!
I'll damn you!
Death will be too good for you!
Is this how Rome treats its hero?
Tell me!
If his life has no
value, what do yours want?
The gods have spoken!
(CHANTING)
For our own safety, we
should return to the palace.
Stay back! Stay back!
(CHANTING)
We had a bargain.
I gave him to you.
You let him live.
And you got what you wanted.
I always get what I want.
Why did you let him live?
You bought a gladiator, not a slave.
My will is my own.
Ah.
How blue is your blood?
Perhaps the heart of
a Roman beats in that chest.
The greatest temple
Rome ever built, the Colosseum,
because this is
what they believe in, power.
They gather here to watch
the strong strike down of the...
There has to be something else.
There is nothing else.
There has to be another Rome.
There is no other Rome.
The dream?
The dream of Rome?
It's an old man's fantasy.
Who are you?
What was your name before
you traded it for a Roman one?
You'll never know.
I have a destiny.
The gods delivered you to me.
You will be my instrument.
I will never be your
instrument in this life for the next.
That will not be my destiny.
But I will see your end.
What else could I do?
He and his pigs were plotting to kill us.
Don't you hear them?
They're calling for our heads.
The Platorians will put down
this crowd like they have every other.
You brought this on us.
Shoo!
Perhaps you should take
Dondys elsewhere to comfort him.
Forgive my brother's outburst.
The disease that infects
his loins has spread to his brain.
Every day gets worse.
I will reason with him.
I see you.
Gotta get on, gotta get on.
Come on, stand up.
Get up, get up, not you.
All right, here you go.
Now, listen to me.
What's the matter?
Nothing's ever mine.
Everything is ours always.
Even in the womb, you try it.
Do I get my umbilicus so
that I couldn't have any more hair?
You remember that, do you?
Certainly.
Sit.
One cannot forget.
My conscience compels me.
What?
Sit.
Your brother means to blame
you in front of the entire Senate.
But I did not do it.
Well, what's
happening in the streets? The chaos.
He's lying.
No testimony can be more
damning than one brother against another.
That's a lie. He always lies.
He can be very persuasive.
So, what will they do to me?
I don't dare imagine, but imagine this.
What will they do to Dondys?
To Dondys?
It's your decision.
(Crowd cheers)
Help me, young man!
Brother.
Put down the blade.
You lie.
Give it to me.
You always lie.
Look at me.
Lie!
Let me break this spell.
Break this spell.
I've always protected you.
Because I love you.
Come back.
Help me.
(Door opens)
Doucheous.
Never could have
imagined the fates would lead us here.
And yet here we are.
Everything has brought us full circle.
You sent me away and you had fate.
Brought me back to
the very ground where he died.
This ring belonged to my father.
He gave it to your
father, Maximus, as a token of trust.
I gave it to Cacius for his valor.
This ring belonged to my wife.
I shall wear it next to yours.
(Chuckles)
I'm truly sorry for Cacius.
I could not see the man.
He was a soldier from...
There was a plan.
He was readying troops at
Ostia under the command of Darius Cixtus.
Troops he was to
lead against the emperors.
Cacius, Maximus, Marcus Aurelius.
They lived and died for Rome.
We all do.
Is it true they intend to kill you?
One man or another has had a sword
against my neck since the day my father died.
But now that I've
found you, it doesn't matter.
I am not afraid.
I've become well versed
in losing the things that I love.
But now that I've found you,
I have no desire to lose you again.
You stand like him.
Alert.
Proud.
I do not have his strength.
I wish that were true.
I wish I were
telling you to free this place.
(Door creaks)
(Door creaks) (Door creaks)
Go now.
Strength and honor.
(Door creaks)
As emperor, I have convened
the Senate to appoint my first consul
and bestow upon
him the power to administer
the military and
civic functions of the empire.
I name Citizen Dardas!
(Dardas creaks)
Hail Dardas!
Hail Dardas.
As second consul,
I name
Citizen
Macronus.
Hail Macronus!
There will be a
triumphal parade to celebrate.
There will be games
and mass executions.
Long live the empire.
Sit down.
I happen to have,
with good fortune and not a little skill,
the remaining emperors here.
I can speak logic to it.
And tame the madness in the street.
But,
do we still order?
I must have power
and command over the Platorian army.
Ballot?
Or hand?
(screams)
Your humble servant.
Put your hands down.
You can sit down.
So,
I'm fine.
Rome must fall.
I need to only give it a push.
And after Rome falls,
what then?
You are your father's child.
His dream of Rome was never a dream.
It was a fiction.
The best revenge is to become
unlike the one who did the injury.
I have made myself unlike your father.
He spoke of dreams,
I speak of truth,
and the only truth in my Rome
is the law of the strongest.
I was owned
by an emperor.
Now I control an empire.
Where else but in Rome can a man do that?
Do you recognize
your father's mark on me?
If there is anything,
if there is anything you need,
in these last hours,
we will provide.
Your death will
clear my path to the throne.
Tomorrow, there will be games,
and at them,
I will prevail.
Robbie!
Can you get me a
message to Ostia by morning?
What is it, Ostia?
There is an army.
I'm asking you to
risk yourself, my friend,
on the surface of something greater.
Ride to Ostia.
Take this ring to General
Darius Sextus, are you listening?
Darius Sextus?
You will know it as a caseus's ring.
And, uh,
who shall I say is
sent me with this ring?
I am Lucius Verus Eradius,
the Prince of Rome.
Tell him I am summoning the
army to the defense of a new republic.
Should I trust you?
Yes.
Should I?
Robbie, I need your keys.
Thank you.
No!
Come back!
Who gave you this?
Lucius Verus Eradius?
The Prince of Rome?
A street kill, Lucerne.
Until she dies,
you will never know peace.
Ever.
If the people love her,
her death will incite the mob.
If she dies and the
streets rise up in anger,
I shall deliver them Caracalla's head,
and the people shall
acclaim me that my friend is...
Shall we?
Yes.
Today will be your last fight, Champion.
And our master has bestowed on you.
The wooden sword of freedom.
But you have to earn it first.
Today, you're
going to defend your mother.
Would all steal a
point? There's still a point!
Wait for me.
In honor of the
acclimation of Emperor Caracalla,
the first council, dondus
and second council, macronuts,
and as punishment for her
conspiracy against the empire,
for her calamities, against
the emperor's imperial bloodline,
and for fermenting military mutiny.
Along with her husband,
the queen will face divine justice
at the hands of the praetorian guard.
I'm not a general,
but we are all soldiers.
And up until now, we have fought for
nothing more than another day's survival.]
What will you have us do?
Well, you can return to yourselves
if you do not wish to fight this battle.
Or,
you can join me
and fight for a
freedom far beyond these walls.
That once was a time when
honor meant something and road.
In this road, I no
longer believe that exists.
We must find it.
And know this,
where death is, we are not.
Where we are, death is not.
By my sword.
Strength another!
Get up, guys!
Let it not be said that
the Emperor is not merciful.
The Queen will be
granted a single gladiator
to defend her
against the Praetorian Guard.
The champion, Hano!
The Queen will be
granted a single gladiator
to defend her
against the Praetorian Guard.
Summon the
cavalry. Put this down at once.
This is war! Real war!
The army of Arces is
advancing just outside of Rome, sir.
We can still out-flank them.
They have only 5,000 troops. No more.
How many are we?
6,000, perhaps more.
Ride to the gate and hold them.
They are barfing fire at their
(yelling)
Go, please, go!
Delicious.
Gimme the bowl.
(yelling)
Go, my son.
Losers.
Pause.
(yelling)
Will nothing kill this barbarian?
Name is Lucius Ferris Aurelius.
The man does not
become emperor by bloodline alone.
He must be taken by
force and kept by force.
Are you such a man as this?
I don't fight for power.
I fight to free Rome from men like you
and to return it to them.
The gods themselves want Rome reborn.
They sent me to fulfill that task.
And what if your
gods sent me here to kill you?
(yelling)
It's time to end this, Maconess.
(yelling) (yelling)
(dramatic music)
[screaming]
Strengthen on her, myself.
[grunting]
[screaming]
[screaming] [gasping]
[grunting]
You look to me to speak.
I know not what to say other
than we have all known too much death.
Let no more blood be
spilled in the name of tyranny.
[screaming]
My grandfather Marcus Aurelius
talked of the dream that would be roamed.
A dream that my father,
Maximus Decimus Meridius, died for.
An ideal.
A city for the many
and a refuge for those in need.
A home worth fighting for.
A home that Maximus
spent his life defending.
That dream is lost.
But dare we...
...dare we...
...rebuild that dream together?
What say you?
Hey!
[screaming]
[screaming] Mother.
[Breathing heavily]
Speak to me, Father.